翻译制作：飞鱼155150666
I love money.
我爱金钱，
I love money more than I love
the things it can buy.
我爱金钱甚至多于它能买到的东西。
Does that surprise you?
让你感到很惊讶吗？
Money. It don't care whether
I'm good or not.
钱,它不在乎我是好还是不好
It don't care whether I snore or not.
不在乎我是否打鼾。
It don't care which god I pray to.
不在乎我祈祷哪个上帝。
There are only three things in this world
with that kind of unconditional acceptance.
这在这个世界上可以无条件接受的只有三件事
Dogs...
狗
...doughnuts...
甜甜圈
...and money.
和钱
Only money is better.
也只有钱是最好的
You know why?
知道为什么吗？
Because it don't make you fat...
因为它不会让你发胖
...and it don't poop all over
the living-room floor.
……它不会便便到卧室的地板上
There's only one thing I like better:
还有的只有一件事，我更喜欢：
Other people's money.
别人口袋里的钱
Hey, guys.
嗨，大伙
Come on.
都到这儿来
All right. Now, squeeze in over here.
好的，现在，往这边挤挤
That's it. I've got to see all your faces.
很好，我看到所有你们的脸。
- How you doing, Tom?
- Happy Thanksgiving, Jorgy!
_你好吗，汤姆？
_感恩节快乐，jorgy!
Happy Thanksgiving, everybody!
大家感恩节快乐！
- Happy Thanksgiving.
- Smile, everybody!
-感恩节快乐！
-笑一个，大家！
Take a good one, Elton.
The stock is up another point and a half!
照好一点，埃尔顿。
股票又上涨了1.5点！
Somebody's up to something, Jorgy.
有人搞鬼，jorgy.
Good news. Stock is up.
Don't worry about it.
股票上涨是好消息，别担心
- Gus, you got your teeth in?
- Ready now!
-格斯，你剔了你的牙吗？
-准备好了吗？
Cheeks up!
茄子！
New England Wire and Cable!
新英格兰电线电缆！（New Englang:美国东北部六州）
新英格兰电线电缆！
Up two points.
上涨两个点。
Wire and Cable up two points.
电线电缆（公司股票）上涨了两个点
- Morning, Mr. Garfield.
- Good morning, Arthur.
-早上好，加菲尔德先生。
-早上好，亚瑟。
Say good morning to Carmen. She's
very happy today, aren't you, my sweet?
跟卡门说，早上好。
她今天很开心，不是吗，亲爱的？
Good morning, Carmen.
早上好，卡门。
- Cranberry juice is fresh today, boss.
- Oh, good.
-今天的红莓汁很新鲜，老板。
-噢，真好！
You never let me down, Arthur.
你从来没让我失望，亚瑟。
You never let me down.
你从来没让我失望。
- Good morning, sir.
- Samuels.
-早上好，先生！
-塞缪尔。
- Good morning, Mr. Garfield.
-早上好，加菲尔德！
- Good morning.
-早上好。
- Good morning, Mr. Garfield.
-早上好，加菲尔德！
- Good morning.
-早上好。
- Morning.
- Good morning, Mr. Garfield.
-早上好。
-早上好，加菲尔德！
Work, work!
去工作，去工作！
- Good morning, Mr. Garfield.
- Morning.
-早上好，加菲尔德！
-早上好。
- Good morning, Mr. Garfield.
- Yeah.
-早上好，加菲尔德！
-yeah。
Good morning, Mr. Garfield.
You look nice today.
-早上好，加菲尔德！
-你今天看上去很不错。
I'm not paying you to be polite, Harriet.
What's happening?
我不会因为你礼貌另付你钱的，哈丽特。
发生什么事了？
- Good morning, Mr. Garfield.
-早上好，加菲尔德！
Morning. Morning.
早上好。
Mr. Holt wants to see you for dinner...
霍尔特先生想在晚餐时见你……
...and the Overly brothers will fly you
to Texas or come here, whichever you want.
……the overly brothers让你回德克萨斯州或是他来这儿，你要哪个？
When I die, put it on my gravestone:
当我死的时候，在我的墓碑上刻上：
- "He never went to Texas."
- Yes, sir. I'll call the engraver.
-“他从来没去过德克萨斯州”
-好的，先生。我会打电话给雕刻师的
- Where's the cinnamon?
- Out of cinnamon.
-肉桂放在哪?
-肉桂吃完了。
If I can't count on Dunkin' Donuts...
如果我不能指望老唐甜甜圈……
...who do I count on?
- Well, you can count on me, sir.
……我能指望谁呢？
-好吧，你可以指望我，先生。
Granger, Trundel Canning. Tell me.
格兰杰，告诉我Trunde罐头的进展。
Trundel is being sued
by the townspeople, sir.
Trundel正被市民起诉，先生
Failed to comply
with environmental restrictions.
因未能遵守环境保护条例
And there are claims of illness
from the citizenry.
并有市民因疾病要求索赔
Good.
太好了
Just before they're carted off to jail,
make a bid.
就在他们被押送进监狱前，出个价
- Yes, sir.
- Angeli.
-好的，先生。
-安吉利
- Yo.
- Eastern Motels. Outstanding shares.
-在
-东方旅馆的流通股是多少
Six million, Mr. Garfield.
Slate owns 2 and a half million.
六百万，加菲尔德先生。
我们拥有2.5百万股。
Mr. Morganstern wants to talk to you.
摩根斯特恩想和你谈谈
I'd rather talk to my mother.
我宁愿和我妈妈谈
- Pfeiffer!
- Yeah.
-菲佛！
-是的。
What about this
New England Wire and Cable?
新英格兰电线电缆公司怎么样了？
It's too beautiful.
Is it booby-trapped?
它太美了。
这是个陷阱吗？
I...
我……
...can't seem to find any problems,
Mr. Garfield.
……好像找不到任何问题，加菲尔德先生。
Neither can I.
我也不能
- Richardson.
- Yes, sir.
-理查德森
-是的，先生
Let's talk to these people.
让我们跟这些人谈谈
Call the man in charge,
whoever he is.
打电话给负责的人，不管他是谁。
Yes, sir. We'll get right on it.
好的，先生，我们马上去做。
New England Wire and Cable.
Good morning.
新英格兰电线电缆公司
早上好
The general manager, please,
请找总经理
That would be Mr. Coles.
那是寇斯先生
- Who shall I say is calling?
- Lawrence Garfield,
-是谁打电话过来呢？
-劳伦斯-加菲尔德
Just one moment, please.
请稍等
- What did he want?
- He wants to come up and see us.
-他想做什么？
-他要来看我们。
Look the place over, he said.
看看这个地方，他说
Well, what's wrong with that?
He's a shareholder.
哦，那有什么问题？
他是股东？
Well, it's not that simple.
额，没那么简单
What this man does is no secret.
这不是什么秘密关于这个人所做的
Bill, you got the jitters.
比尔，你太紧张了
Wall Street's in the liquidation business
these days, Jorgy.
华尔街专门从事清算业务的，jorgy.
My father founded this company
81 years ago.
在81年前，我父亲就创办了这家公司。
- I took over 28 years ago...
- I know.
-28年前我接手了……
-我知道。
I control this company,
and nobody's gonna liquidate us.
我控制这家公司，没人能清算我们。
What a shit pit.
什么样的一个屎坑
Look at this.
看这个
哇哦，看看这个
I haven't seen a place this classy
since I left the Bronx.
自从我离开纽约，我还从没见过这样的地方。
Welcome to New England Wire and Cable.
欢迎关临新英格兰电线电缆公司
I'm Bea Sullivan, Mr. Jorgenson's assistant.
我是沙利文，乔根森先生的助手
- How do you do?
- I do good.
-你怎么样？
-我很好。
Would you like to invite your chauffeur in
to keep warm?
你想邀请你的司机进来温和一下吗？
No, no. He's a yard chauffeur, honey.
哦，不，他是派遣司机，亲爱的。
Bring him inside, you spoil him.
把他带进来，你会宠坏他的
Is there a Dunkin' Donuts in this town?
在这个镇上有老唐甜甜圈吗？
Dunkin' Donuts? No, I don't think so.
老唐甜甜圈？不，我不认为有。
- Krispy Kreme, something?
- I'm afraid not.
-像甜甜圈一样的东西？
-恐怕没有。
But we have coffee,
and Emma might have a breakfast roll.
但我们有咖啡，还有艾玛会给准备一份早餐
Breakfast roll?
自助早餐？
Do you have an elevator?
你们有电梯吗？
I'm embarrassed to tell you,
it's out of order. You know elevators.
我非常遗憾的告诉你，
它出故障了，你知道电梯会的
Any oxygen?
有没有氧气？呼……呼……
You should have warned me.
I'd have brought a paramedic.
你应该告诉我，我会带护理一起来的，
Is it much further?
I'd like to get there before dark.
还很远吗?
我想在天黑之前到达那里。
Jorgy, this is Mr. Garfield.
Jorgy,这是加菲尔德先生。
Mr. Garfield, Andrew Jorgenson,
our chairman.
加菲尔德先生，安得烈・乔根林，我们的主席。
Call me Jorgy. Everybody else does.
Sorry about the elevator.
叫我jorgy,像其他人一样。
关于电梯我感到抱歉。
- It has a mind of its own.
- Mr. Coles, president and general manager.
-它有它自己的心灵。
-寇斯先生，董事长兼总经理。
- Emma, bring in the coffee!
- Nice to meet you.
-艾玛，把咖啡带进来！
-见到你很高兴。
Last limousine we saw here
was in '48...
我们上一次在这里看到豪华轿车是在‘48……
...when Truman was running for president.
- That's right.
……杜鲁门在竞选总统时。
-对
He stood right out there on those stairs,
exactly where you were.
他站在楼梯那，就在你们那里
- Is that so?
- Yep.
-真是这样的吗？
-是的。
That was the golden age.
Rebuilding America and all that.
那是黄金时代。
美国在重建所有
Old Harry made a great speech that day.
那一天老哈里做了一个伟大的演讲。
- Is that so?
- Oh, yes. He was very impressive.
-真是这样吗?
-啊，是的，他给人很深刻的印象。
He's the only Democrat
Bea and I ever voted for.
他是我投票的唯一的民主党
Do you know much about
the wire and cable business, Mr. Garfield?
你知道多少关于电线电缆企业，加菲尔德先生？
I know if the cable's out of whack,
the elevator don't go up.
-我知道如果电缆失衡，电梯就上不去。
- I'm thinking about the doughnuts.
- Doughnuts?
-我在想甜甜圈。
-甜甜圈？
Mr. Garfield was wondering if we had any.
如果我们有的话，加菲尔德先生想要一些。
- Bill, do we have doughnuts?
- I don't think so.
-比尔，我们有甜甜圈？
-我不这么认为。
How's that coffee coming along?
咖啡好了吗？
- Here we are, Mr. Garfield.
- Thank you.
-给你，加菲尔德先生
-谢谢。
- Sugar and cream?
- Sugar. I'll take care of it.
-加糖和牛奶吗？
-加糖吧，我自己来好了。
- Thank you, Emma.
- I could have Emma get doughnuts.
-谢谢你，艾玛。
-我能让艾玛给你弄一个甜甜圈。
No, no. Why don't we get down
to business.
不，不，我们为什么不坐下来谈谈关于生意的事
What's the matter?
You're not interested in doughnuts?
这有什么关系？
你对甜甜圈不感兴趣？
- Would you like me to get some doughnuts?
- No. Never mind, Emma.
-你想要我去弄一些甜甜圈吗？
-不，没关系，艾玛。
You're right.
你说的对。
- Let's talk business.
- Good idea.
-我们来谈谈生意。
-这提议不错。
What business are we talking about?
谈什么样的生意呢？
Good coffee.
咖啡不错
Well, let's put it this way:
好吧，让我们这么说吧：
Back in New York, I got a computer.
Her name is Carmen.
从纽约说起，我有一台电脑，她的名字叫卡门
Every morning, right after I brush my teeth,
I punch out:
每天早晨，当我刷完牙的时候，我打开它：
"Carmen, computer on the wall,
who's the fairest of them all?"
“卡门，墙上的电脑，谁是最美丽的人？”
Now, most mornings, she spits out,
"Garfield, you're the fairest."
现在，大多数早晨，她输出，
“加菲尔德，你是最美的。”
But three weeks ago, she said:
但三个星期前，她说：
"Garfield, Garfield, scratch your balls.
“加菲尔德，加菲尔备，把你的球。
New England..." Pardon me. "New England
Wire and Cable is the fairest of them all."
新英格兰……”对不起“新英格兰电线电缆公司是最美丽的人。”
New England Wire and Cable?
新英格兰电线电缆公司？
I said, "What's it worth?"
So she showed me the numbers.
我说，“它有什么价值？”
接着她给我展示了数据。
You got equipment here
that costs $ 1 2O million.
你这儿的设备花了120百万美元买来的
Even at salvage,
it's worth 3O, 35 million.
即使是残值，它现在的价值30，35百万美元
- Can I use that blackboard over there?
- Yeah, go ahead.
-我可以使用黑板吗？
-是的，去吧。
Thank you.
谢谢
Come with me.
Carmen will educate us.
跟我来。
卡门将教育我们。
Gonna erase this stuff here.
先清除这里的东西。
Here.
这里。
Let's put down 3O million.
让我们写下30百万
- How many acres you got?
- A hundred and ten.
-你有多少占地面积？
-110英亩
Carmen and I figure,
even as farmland, grazing land...
卡门和我认为，即便是农田，牧场……
...it's worth 1 O million.
……它价值10百万美元。
- Is that fair?
- Yeah.
-这公平吧？
-是的。
Let's lay the 1 O under the 3O.
That makes 4O million.
我们把10写到30下面。
得到40百万美元。
You bought some other companies,
didn't you, Bill?
比尔，你是不是买了一些其它公司？
You have a plumbing, an electrical
and some kind of adhesive company.
你有一个水暖，电器和一些胶类公司
Boring, but all making a decent profit.
无聊的，但是都有一个像样的利润
Carmen says they're worth
another 8O mil.
卡门说，他们的价值80百万美元
Let's put the 8O under the 4O.
把80写在40下面
And you have working capital of 25 million,
1 O of it in cash.
你有25百万的营运资本，其中现金占10%。
Let's put down 25 million,
add them up and see what you got.
我们再把25百万写在下面
加起来，看看你有什么
$ 1 25 million.
125百万美元。
The only bad news is...
唯一的坏消息是……
...that this wire and cable division
isn't making a profit...
……这电线电缆公司没有利润……
...and all the other divisions
have to support you.
所有其它部门都不得不支持你。
Now, as a stockholder,
that doesn't make me very happy.
现在，作为一个股东。
这并不让我很高兴
Are you finished, Mr. Garfield?
你讲完了吗，加菲尔德先生？
No, I'm not, Bill.
不，我没有，比尔
Let's say Carmen was suffering
from premenstrual syndrome.
让我们说卡门正经受经前综合征的痛苦
No offense. A little nuts.
没有过错，有一点狂热
Let's say she was too optimistic.
让我们说她太乐观
Let's knock off 25 million.
Here we go.
让我们去掉25百万
让我们开始吧
Let's make it...
让我们使它……
...$ 1 OO million.
……成100百万的对象
A nice round number.
I like nice round numbers.
一个不错的整数。
我喜欢好的整数。
Any debt? No.
任何债务? 没有。
Any lawsuits?
Any environmental bullshit?
任何诉讼? 环保争议？
You throwing your garbage in the water?
Of course not. Not you.
你把垃圾扔进水中了吗？
当然不，不是你。
What about pension liabilities?
关于养老金负债?
Carmen says you're fully funded.
卡门说，你有充分的资金。
You people are dreams.
你的人有梦想
- I think this meeting is over.
- No, no, wait a minute.
-我认为这次会结束了
-不， 不，等一下。
Here comes the fun part.
有乐趣的部分在这里
- How many shares outstanding you got?
- Four million.
-你有多少股份
-四百万
Divide 4 million into 1 OO million,
what do you get?
四百万被一百百万除，你得到了什么？
- Twenty-five.
- Good.
-二十五
-好的
That means each share is worth $ 25.
那意味着每股价值25美元。
But that was all foreplay.
Let's go for the real thing.
但这都是前戏。
让我们去做真实的东西
The stock was 1 O when I woke up
three weeks ago.
三星期前，当我醒来的时候股票价格是10美金
That's a 1 O for a $ 25 item.
这是一个用10美金就可以买到25美金的项目
What a sale.
什么是营销
Something worth $ 25,
I can buy it for 1 O.
价值25美元的东西，我用10美元就能买到
The company's not for sale,
Mr. Garfield.
公司是不出售的
加菲尔德先生。
I don't want your company, Jorgy.
我不想要你的公司，jorgy
I just want what
every other stockholder wants:
我只想要每个其它股东想要的
- I wanna make money.
- You are making money, Mr. Garfield.
-我想赚钱。
-你在赚钱，加菲尔德先生
You bought the stock at 1 O.
It's now 14.
你在10美元每股时买进
现在是14美元每股了
The stock is 14 because I'm buying it.
股价涨到14，是因为我买了它
I'm doing my part. Now you do yours.
我做了我这部分，现在你做你那部分了。
Get rid of this wire and cable division.
It's a financial cancer.
摆脱这种电线电缆公司
它是一个财务癌症。
Would you excuse us, please?
I want to talk to Mr. Garfield alone.
你能原谅我吗？
我想跟加菲尔德先生单独谈谈
What the hell do you think you're doing,
you little son of a bitch?
他妈的你到底想干什么，你这个小混蛋？
You can't come into my town, my plant,
take my company.
你不能来我的镇，我的工厂,拿走我的公司。
- You can't do that.
- What, you been living on Mars, Jorgy?
-你不能那样做
-什么，你一直生活在火星上吗，jorgy?
It's called a corporate takeover.
它被称为公司收购
I know what it's called,
and I'm not gonna let you do it.
我知道它叫什么，我不想让你做。
It's simple. I do it all the time.
很简单，我一直在做它。
Well, do it someplace else.
I'm not gonna commit suicide.
咽，你到别的地方做吧，我不想自杀
Don't think of it as suicide.
不要认为这是自杀。
Think of it as euthanasia.
把它想成是安乐死。
Get out.
你给我滚出去
Get out before I throw you out.
快滚出去，在我把你扔出去前
Where are you going?
We're just doing business.
你去哪儿？
我们只是在做生意。
Business? With you?
生意？和你吗?
I got a company to run.
我经常运营公司
Yeah, well, that's my point.
是啊，嗯，这是我的观点。
I don't like the way my company's
being run!
我不喜欢我的公司这样运行！
And you better get your elevator fixed!
你最好把你的电梯安装好！
There's a goddamn fire raging here,
and this whole industry's up in flames!
有一个该死的大火在这里，全行业都在火焰中！
And you call the fire department,
and who shows up? Nobody.
你打电话给消防部门，谁来了？没有人。
Because they're all in Japan
and Singapore and Malaysia...
因为他们都是在日本，新加坡和马来西亚……
...and Taiwan and every other shithole
where they're crazy about pollution.
……台湾和其他鬼地方，他们在那疯狂的污染
And while that inferno is raging,
you're out in front...
当大火在狂疯的时候，
你正在……
...mowing the lawn, tidying up,
playing with your putz on my money!
用我的钱修剪草坪，整理……，玩你的球
- You'd think I was asking him for a loan.
- Good day, Mr. Garfield.
-你以为我是问他贷款
-美好的一天，加菲尔德先生。
I'm not a long-term player.
我不是一个长期的球员。
They give us trouble today?
他们今天给我们制造麻烦了吗？
They're not gonna send us back
to the Bronx, Arthur.
他们不会送我们回纽约了，亚瑟。
Don't scare me there, Mr. G.
不要在这吓我，G先生
Richardson, I wanna buy up
New England Wire and Cable.
理查德森，我想买新英格兰电线电缆公司
Buy everything you can.
买所有你能买的
File a goddamned 1 3D.
文件的一个该死的1个三维(不谓何解)
- I wanna finish this one quick.
- We're on it,
-我想尽快完成这一块
-我们正在做
Well, it's official.
嗯，这是正式的。
Our friend Garfield's intent
is to take over the company.
我们的朋友加菲尔德意图接管公司。
He's filed his 1 3D with the SEC.
他提出了1个三维的秒(不知何意)
He now owns 1 2 percent of us.
他现在拥有我们12%的股份
What do you wanna do?
你想做什么？
I own 2O percent.
我拥有20%的股份
Jorgy, we've got to protect ourselves.
jorgy,我们必须保护自己。
- We need legal advice.
- We have lawyers.
-我们需要法律咨询。
-我们有律师。
They're not equipped for this.
他们不善长这。
- We need the best.
- We want to call Kate.
-我们需要最好的。
-我们要打电话给凯特。
Let me.
让我去。
What makes you think she'll come?
是什么让你觉得她会来？
I'll tell her we need her.
我告诉她我们需要她。
We're family.
我们是一家人。
Flamboyant L's and M's.
华丽的L 和 M。
Loves to write "million," doesn't he?
受写“百万，”他是吗？
We've never seen a man like that.
我们从来没有见过这样的人
He's like something out of a comic book.
他就像一本漫画书。
So they say.
他们是这么说的。
- Hello, Kate.
- Jorgy.
-你好，凯特
-jorgy
Thanks for coming.
谢谢你能来。
Doesn't she look splendid?
她看上去是不是很杰出？
I have to be back in the city by 5.
Would you mind if we get right down to it?
我要在5点回到城市。
你介意我们现在就开始着手吗？
You're in charge, Kate.
照你说的，凯特
Given that someone is interested
in moving in on you...
假设某人想要入侵你……
...you've no choice
but to protect yourself.
……你除了保护自己外，没有其它选择
You have some options.
你有一些选项
For openers, I recommend changing
your state of incorporation...
首先，我建议改变你的注册国……
...from Rhode Island to Delaware.
- Why Delaware?
……从罗得州到特拉华。
-为什么是特华？
That's a good idea.
Strong anti-takeover legislation in Delaware.
好主意！
在特拉华州有强烈的反收购立法。
And that way we're not playing dead.
这样我们不玩死
- Who the hell is playing dead?
- You have to protect yourself.
-到底是谁玩？
-你必须保护自己。
- By running away to Delaware?
- Jorgy, it's only on paper.
-离家出走到特拉华州？
-jorgy,它只是在纸上。
This company was founded in Rhode Island.
It will remain in Rhode Island.
本公司成立在罗得岛。
它将继续在罗得岛。
I'm talking about Delaware, not Nairobi.
Come on.
我说的是特拉华，不是内罗毕。
I own 2O percent of this company.
我拥有这公司20%的股份。
The board owns another 5,
the employees another 5 percent.
董事会拥有另外5%，工会拥有另一个5%.
That's 3O percent.
Now, how can this man get control?
那就是30%
现在，这个人怎么能得到控制权？
What do you want? Do you want me
to negotiate a deal or not?
你想怎么样？你要我谈判一项协议或不？
But there's no deal to be made.
但是这儿没有可做的协议
He's knocking at your door.
他在敲你的门
If you don't answer it,
it's the same as inviting him in.
如果你不回答，等同于邀请他进来。
Listen to her, Jorgy.
听她的，jorgy
There's no deal to be made
with predators.
与食肉动物没什么协议可做的
You kill it, or it kills you.
你杀了它，或者它杀了你。
Well, what do you suggest?
好吧，你有什么意见？
Make it worth his while to leave.
使它值得自己离开
How? How? What do you mean?
怎么做？怎么做？你的意思是？
Pay him off.
Buy him out at a profit.
偿付让他离开。
为他的利润买单，让他出局。
It's greenmail, Jorgy,
but it's done all the time.
就是绿票讹诈。
但是这最后还是完成了
- It's terrorism, and I won't do it!
- We have other options, don't we?
-这是恐怖主义，我不会做的！
-我们有其他选择吗？
Well, you're gonna lose your company.
嗯，你将会失去你的公司。
Like hell I am.
我喜欢地狱吗
You, as they say in the street,
are in play.
你正在比赛，像他们在大街上说的
Garfield put you there.
加菲尔德让你在这儿（跟他比赛）
And now I'm here as your lawyer.
现在我在这作为你的律师
Isn't that a hell of an irony?
这是不是一个糟透的讽刺？
Me trying to save your company.
我正试图拯救你的公司
Well, I can do it.
是的，这是我能做的
Yeah?
是
A Miss Sullivan
from Hudson,  Bradley and Flint is here,
在这里有一位从哈得逊，布拉德利来的沙利文小姐
And Granger wants to see you
about Trundel,
还有，格兰杰因为Trundel的事想见你
Your suits are ready for a fitting,
Can they come up at 5?
你的衣服需要试衣，他们可以5点来吗？
Yeah, 5:OO is okay. But tell them not to
send the blind son of a bitch with the pins.
是的，5点可以。但是告诉他们不要派狗娘养的愚昧的别针来
- Right, no pins,
- And tell Granger, if he wants to see me...
-好的，不要针脚
-告诉格兰杰，如果他想见我……
...he better make more sense than last time,
or he can get on unemployment.
……他最好比上次做得更有意义，或者他将失业。
Shall I use those exact words, sir?
我要用这些话，先生？
Send in Hudson, Bradley and Flint.
让哈得逊，布拉德利的人进来
Wow.
噢
You know what kills me? I've done
maybe seven, eight deals like this before...
你知道我讨厌什么吗?
这样的事之前我大概遇上了七、八件……
...and you know who I negotiate with?
……你知道谁与我洽谈？
Skinny little joggers with contact lenses,
all stinking from the same aftershave.
苗条的着贴身小套装，同样的后须水的味道
- I'm Kate Sullivan.
- I know.
-我是凯特沙利文
-我知道
- Want a cigarette?
- No, thank you.
-要一支烟吗？
-不，谢谢
Don't let me stop you.
别让我阻止你。
Why would you stop me?
为什么要阻止我？
What are you, a fucking lawyer?
你是什么，一个他妈的律师？
Depends on who I'm with.
取决于我和谁在一起
Welcome to my life.
欢迎来到我的生活
So, what's it gonna be?
因此，接下来是什么？
Sue, settle, defend?
起诉，协议，辩护?
I came to talk.
我是来对话的。
Oh, that's trouble.
哦，那就麻烦了
Lawyers wanna talk,
nothing but trouble.
律师想谈，只有麻烦
- How about a doughnut?
- No, thanks.
-来一个甜甜圈？
-不了，谢谢。
- Why, are you a health-food freak?
- No, just not hungry.
-为什么，你是保健食品狂吗？
-不，只是不饿。
- You have to be hungry to eat a doughnut?
- You don't?
-你必须饿了才吃一个甜甜圈吗?
-你不吗？
What, are you shitting me?
什么，你在取笑我吗?
I never heard of such a thing,
have to be hungry.
我从未听说过这样的事情，必须是饥饿才吃
Why? It don't taste better that way.
为什么？这样不更美味吗
- How would you know?
- What do you want?
-你怎么知道？
-你想怎么样？
- I need a month.
- Get lost.
-我需要一个月
-不行
I just got involved. I need time to get
everybody's act together.
我只是参与了，我需要时间去让大家一起行动。
My act is together.
我的行为是在一起的。
If you give me some time,
I think we can work something out.
如果你给我一点时间，我觉得我们可以做点什么。
Settle?
协议？
Work something out.
工作出一些东西
- I only settle when I'm in trouble.
- Or when it makes sense.
-当我处在麻烦中的时候我才协议。
-或者这样做有意义。
It only makes sense when I'm in trouble.
只我我在麻烦中的时候它才有意义
Well, if you prefer, we'll go to court.
好吧，如果你喜欢，我们可以法庭上见
Get an injunction, have a fight.
All kinds of allegations.
申请一个禁令，来一场战斗。
各种指控。
Costs them, costs you, and for what?
让他们花费，让你花费，这样做又有什么好处？
I live in court.
You gotta do better than that.
我住在法院。
你要做的比这更好。
I won't love you anymore.
我不会再爱你
- Two weeks.
- Standstill agreement.
-两周
-暂停偿付协议
- Both sides.
- No more buying.
-双方
-别买更多
- Two weeks.
- Thank you.
-两周
-谢谢
Whoa, where are you going?
哇，你要去哪里？
We haven't talked about
what I wanna talk about.
我们还没聊我想说的。
- What's that?
- You and me sweating between satin sheets.
-聊什么
-我和你在缎子床单上出汗。
Garfield, put your hand between your legs.
加菲尔德，把你的手放在你的腿中间。
Do it!
做啊
Good. Now look directly down
at that little guy...
很好，现在，直拉看下这小家伙……
...and you say, "You must behave yourself
when you're in the presence of a lady."
……你说，“你必须表现的像绅士当你在女士面前。”
Garfield, if you don't say exactly that
right now, I'm resigning from this case.
加菲尔德，如果你不照我说的做，我会辞退这个案例。
- You must behave yourself...
-你必须表现的像绅士……
...when you're in the presence...
……当你在一个女士面前……
...of a lady.
See? Not so hard.
看到了吗？不是很难。
See you in two weeks.
两周后见。
Wow! Did you see that, Carmen?
哇！你看到了吗，卡门？
I'm in love, I'm in love.
我恋爱了，我恋爱了。
- Goodbye, Miss Sullivan.
- Goodbye.
-再见，沙利文小姐。
-再见。
Call Erickson. Tell him to arrange
some money through the Royal Bank.
打电话给埃里克森。告诉他通过皇家银行安排一些钱。
Don't pay more than we did
on Fleetwood Furniture.
费用不要超过我们做佛利特伍德家俱时的
Then call Hathaway.
然后打电话给哈撒伟
Tell him I want to make a tender offer
for New England Wire and Cable.
告诉他，我想为新英格兰电线电缆公司做一下投标报价
Don't put it under our name.
不要把我们的名字写进去
Label it OPM Holdings.
标签OPM控股
But what if she finds out
we broke the agreement?
但如果她发现我们打破协议呢？
Richardson, what were you,
born yesterday?
理查德森，你怎么了，你是出生在昨天吗？
What do you think she's doing?
你觉得她在做什么？
That kewpie doll's up to no good.
Do it.
丘比娃娃不怀好意。
做就是了。
I got us an extra two weeks.
Now we have to move fast.
我为我们多争取了两周时间。
现在我们们必须快速行动。
Get the board to buy up as many shares
as they can.
让董事会尽所能的买入更多的股份。
Use your own working capital.
用你的营运资金
No,  that's not what
those dollars are for,
不，那些钱不是做这个用的，
- That's our safety net,
- Then borrow the money.
-那是我们的安全网
-再借点钱
- No borrowing.
- Andrew, listen to her. She's making sense.
-不借钱。
-安得烈，听她的，她这样做有意义
For every share you acquire,
it's one less for Garfield,
你每多获得一份股份，加菲尔德就少一份股份。
The more we buy, the less for him.
我们买的越多，他就越少。
The more it costs, the less profit he makes.
成本越高，他的利润就越少。
So get the stock up.
这样股价就上去了。
And, Mom, make sure to buy it
through an out-of-state broker.
然后，妈妈，确保要通过一个外州的经纪人买入
I don't wanna borrow money.
We've been debt-free since the depression.
我不想借钱
自从萧条期，我们就没有债务了。
But see, that's the trouble, Jorgy.
但看吧，那就是问题，jorgy.
It's your gorgeous balance sheet
that makes you so attractive.
就是你这华丽的资产负债表让你变得这么有吸引力。
And, Mom, get letters out
to the shareholders.
妈妈，把信发给股东。
Tell them how great business is
and how wonderful the future looks,
告诉他们这是多好的生意，看上去前景多少好。
- I'll do it.
- Great,
-我会做的
-太好了
I'll call you tomorrow.
Good night.
我明天再联系你，晚安。
Good morning, honey.
早上好，亲爱的
How you doing this morning, huh?
你今天早上怎么样了，嗯？
You got it up again.
你又上涨了。
Another point and a half.
又一个1.5点
- Pfeiffer.
- Good morning, Mr. Garfield.
-菲佛。
-早上好，加菲尔德先生
- Woody.
- Good morning, Mr. Garfield.
-伍迪
-早上好，加菲尔德先生
- Harriet.
- Good morning.
-哈丽特
-早上好
Miss Sullivan is gonna call
tomorrow morning.
沙利文小姐明早会打电话来。
You tell her I'm not taking calls.
你告诉她我不接电话
Then, when she comes over here
and tries to storm into the office...
如果，她来这里，并试图闯入办公室……
...you try to keep her out.
But then let her push past.
……你要试图阻止她，但最后让她通过。
Don't worry, she's desperate but harmless.
Find out where she lives and call a florist.
别担心，她会有点绝望但无害。
找出她住在哪里，打电话给花店。
- Florist?
- Florist.
-花店?
-花店。
You have a good evening, Miss Sullivan.
祝你有一个美好的夜晚，沙利文小姐。
- Hello, Michael.
- Oh, Miss Sullivan, here.
-你好，迈克尔。
-哦，沙利文，在这里。
- Somebody brought these by for you.
- Oh, thank you.
-有人把这些给你。
-哦，谢谢
- Good night.
-晚安。
- Good morning.
-早上好。
- You ruthless son of a bitch!
- Excuse me?
-你这混蛋！
-怎么了？
Jeez, I wonder what her problem is.
耶稣啊，我不知道她有什么问题。
All right, all right.
好的，好的。
Excuse me.
抱歉。
- Hello, Miss Sullivan, may I help you?
- No, I'm sorry. I don't care. I will...
-你好,沙利文小姐，我可以帮你吗？
-不，抱歉。我不在乎，我……
- I don't care! I'm not gonna...
- It's all right, Harriet.
-我不在乎！我不是想要……
-没关系的，哈丽特。
- You can't go in.
- It's not all right, you hypocrite! You lied!
-你不能进去。
-这并不好，你这假冒的伪善人，你说谎了！
- But, baby-poo...
- We had an agreement.
-但是，宝贝……
-我们有过协议的。
We had a standstill!
No more buying!
我们都要停下来，不是更多的买入！
- OPM Holdings? You know nothing about it?
- OPM?
-OPM 控股？你对此一无所知？
-OPM？
- Not a lot to know.
- You broke the agreement!
-一点也不知道。
-你破坏了协议！
You embarrassed me with my firm.
You embarrassed me with my clients!
你让我对我公司很窘。
你让我对我的客户很窘！
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
等等，等等。
Don't come on so holier-than-thou with me.
别对我假仁假义的
What am I supposed to do,
sit here while you drive up the stock?
我能怎么办，坐在这里干等你抬高股价？
- I did no such thing.
- You're full of shit.
-我没有做这种事。
-你在胡扯
All that buying coming from some little
cockamamie brokerage firm in Rhode Island?
所有买入都来自罗得岛的众多的经纪公司？
You'd think you'd use an out-of-state firm.
你肯定想过要用一个外州的注册
I know nothing about that.
我对此事一无所知
Give me a break.
你就省省吧
Who am I dealing with here,
Mother Teresa?
我是在与谁打交道，特瑞萨修女？
You want to play the game,
learn to play it right.
你想玩这游戏，学会如何玩好它。
Oh, is that what you call it,
a game?
哦，这就是你所说的，一场游戏？
You're damn right.
The best game in the world.
你说对了，这世上最棒的游戏。
I'll teach you. It's easy.
我来教你，很容易。
You make as much as you can
for as long as you can.
你要尽你所能的尽可能的多做
And then what?
然后呢？
"And then what?"
然后？
Whoever has the most when he dies,
wins.
当他死亡或胜利的时候，那个人将拥有更多
Look. It's the American way.
看吧，这就是美国方式
I'm doing my job.
我正的做我的工作
I'm a capitalist.
我是一个资本家
I'm simply following
the law of free enterprise.
我只是自由企业法则的追随者
What law is that?
什么法则？
Survival of the fittest.
适者生存
Maybe some people don't see it that way.
也许有人没不这样认为
Maybe they don't see it
as survival of the fittest.
也许他们并没有把它看成是适者生存
- Maybe they see it as survival of the fattest!
- Oh, Katie, why are you so hard on me?
-也许他们认为是为了肥胖而生存呢？
-哦，凯蒂，为什么要为难我呢？
Because you're not nice.
因为你不是一个好人
Since when do you have to be nice
to be right?
从什么时候起你认为你正确所以你是好人了？
You're not right.
You're what's happening.
你说的不对。
我说的是你。
One day we'll smarten up and pass some
laws and put you out of business.
总有一天我们会变得精明并通过一些法律让你出局
They can pass all the laws they want.
他们可以通过所有他们想通过的法律
All they can do is change the rules.
他们所能做的就是改变规则
They can never stop the game.
他们永远不会阻止这个游戏
I don't go away. I adapt.
我不走开，我适应它
Ten years from now, they'll be studying
you at the Wharton School.
若干年后，在沃顿商学院的学生
They'll call it the Garfield Era...
他们会把这称作为加菲尔德时代……
...and rinse their mouths out
when they leave the room!
当他们毕业的的时候他们会唾弃它
- I'll see you in court!
- Oh, Katie.
-我会在法庭上见你！
-哦，凯蒂
Don't leave.
We haven't talked about sex yet.
别走啊，我们至今还没有谈关于上床的事呢
- At least have a doughnut.
- Stuff it!
-至少来一个甜甜圈。
-你吃个够吧！
Come on. Don't be a poor loser!
加油，不要成为一个糟糕的失败者！
Lying to protect your client
is just doing a good job. I understand that.
对你要保护的客户撒谎是一项好工作，这我理解
You didn't even ask me
what OPM stands for.
你甚至没有问我什么是OPM
Other people's money!
别人的钱！
All right, come on, come on!
Let's go!
好了，来吧，来吧！
我们进去！
- Work, work, work!
- Yes, sir!
-去工作，去工作，去工作！
-是的，先生！
Gotcha! Oh, yes.
知道了！哦，不错。
How do you have them?
你怎么了？
Two years ago, he tried to take over
Westridge Corporation.
两年前，他试图接管Westridge公司
He was put under indictment for failing
to disclose his 1 3D.
他被起诉因为没有披露他的1 3D.
- What's this?
- Christmas list.
-这是什么？
-对诞节名单。
- What did they do?
- Nothing. Dropped the charges.
-他们当时做了什么？
-没什么，撤销控诉。
- Investors get hurt?
- Nope.
-投资者受伤？
-不。
If the charges were dropped,
it's a technicality.
指控是否被撤销，这是技术细节
He was required to disclose.
他被要求披露
Gerber's in prison, Richard.
加宝在监狱里，李察。
Judge Pollard ain't gonna give you
a restraining order based on a technicality.
波拉德法官不会根据这个细节给你一个禁令
We are a nation of laws, Marcia.
我们是一个法制国家，玛西亚。
Ultimately, those laws come down
to technicalities.
最终，对技术细节的法律会出台的。
Without those technicalities,
what do we have?
没有这些细节，我们会有什么呢？
Anarchy.
无政府状态
Garfield.
加菲尔德
- Anarchy? That's the basis for your brief?
- Correct.
-无政府状态？这就是你的陈述依据？
-正确。
Honeybunch, you better write
a fantastic brief.
宝贝，你最好写一个神奇的陈述。
- I intend to.
- You wanna send anything to Garfield?
-我打算去做
-你想送些礼物给加菲尔德吗?
Yeah. A court order.
的是，法庭传票。
Do the Japanese celebrate Christmas?
日本人也庆祝圣诞吗？
No, but I hear they're buying it.
没有，但是听说他们在购买它。
I had nothing to do with any of this.
我没有做任何这事
Pfeiffer comes walking in...
菲佛走进来了……
TRO.
禁制令
Temporary restraining order.
临时禁令
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
Some crew I've got.
我有一些成员。
Seventeen lawyers...
十七个律师……
...on retainer.
……要付聘金的。
And you manage to work it out...
你们是不是要想些办法……
...so that in a free market...
……在这样的自由市场……
...a so-called free country...
……所谓自由的国家……
...I can't buy some shit-ass stock
every other asshole can buy.
……我不能买些垃圾股票但其它混蛋可以买。
Congratulations.
庆祝吧。
You're destroying the capitalist system.
你们正摧毁资本主义制度
While everybody else
in the world is embracing it...
当世界上的其它人正拥抱它的时候……
...my boys and girls are fucking it up!
……我的人却不知道干什么去了！
You know what happens
when capitalism gets fucked up?
你知道当资本主义被遏制的时候会发生什么吗？
The communists come back.
就回到共产党人的时代了
They come out of the bushes.
Don't kid yourself.
他们来自丛林，别欺骗自己。
They're waiting in there.
他们就在那等着
But maybe that's not so bad.
但也许并不那么坏。
Because you know what happens
when the commies take over?
因为当共产党接管的时候你会知道发生什么事了？
The first thing they do
is shoot all the lawyers!
他们做的第一件事就是干掉所有的律师！
And if they miss any of you,
I'll do it myself!
如果他们漏了你们中的哪一个，我会自己来处理！
Now let's see if we can get
this small-town judge...
现在让我们看看能否让这个小镇的法官……
...to change his fucking mind!
……改变操他的主意！
Come on.
进行吧。
It wasn't me!
I was in San Francisco!
这不是我干的！
我当时在三藩！
Mr, Garfield,
a Miss Sullivan is on the line,
加菲尔德先生，沙利文小姐在线上，
- Yes.
- Hello, Lawrence.
-嗯
-嗨，劳伦斯
We're here in the office,
toasting Judge Pollard's decision,
我们在这里的办公室庆祝波拉德法官的决定，
Stop gloating. It doesn't become you.
不要幸灾乐祸，你不会得逞的。
Don't be a poor loser,
不要变成一个糟糕的失败者，
I got you on a technicality. Not bad
for some broad wet behind the ears.
我得到一个关于你的内幕，对那些喜欢道听途说的来说也计会不错
I'd like to talk,
我愿理谈谈，
I have no time for talk. My days are full.
我没有时间和你谈，我今天的安装很满。
- I'll buy you a doughnut.
- I'm not hungry.
-我请你吃甜甜圈
-我不饿
Since when do you have to be hungry
to have a doughnut?
从什么时候起你要饿了才吃甜甜圈了？
Shut up,
住口，
Stop pouting. I'll buy you dinner.
别翻脸啊，我请你吃甜甜圈。
Name the place.
I have a proposition for you.
告诉我地方，我给你一个提议。
You're trying to seduce me.
你在引诱我.
You have a nice laugh.
你笑的很愉快。
My house, 8: OO.
我家，早8点
How about Lutece?
叫Lutece的饭店怎么样？
I wanna talk to somebody,
I go to them.
我想和某人谈，我去看他们
You wanna talk, come to me, 8: OO.
你想谈，到我这来，8点
I'll come for 2O minutes.
That's all I need. Strictly business.
大概要二十分钟
我要谈的是纯脆的生意。
Twenty minutes, my place,  8:OO,
二十分钟，我的地方，8点
- 5:3O
- 5:3O?
-五点半
-五点半？
- Funerals are at 5:3O. Seven.
- Six,
-葬礼才在5:30,七点怎么样
-六点
- I gotta wash my face.
- 8:3O.
-我还要洗脸
-八点半
- Deal.
-成交
Harriet!
哈丽特
Get me my barber.
Get me my manicurist.
给我找理发师，美甲师
Call Arthur. She's coming to the house.
打电话给亚瑟，她要来我家
- Miss Sullivan.
- That's me.
-沙利文小姐
-这就是我
- Come on in. The boss is expecting you.
- Thank you.
-进来吧，老板正在等你
-谢谢
- Mr. G will be right with you.
- Thank you.
-G先生会在这里见你
-谢谢
Gloria Taylor.
凯莱泰勒
Quarterback's girlfriend.
四分卫的女朋友。
All that putz wanted to do was
take her pants off in the back seat...
当其它笨蛋想着在后座上把她裤子脱掉的时……
...while I was ready to feed her...
……我正准供养她……
...protect her,
put jewels around her neck.
……保护她，为她戴上项链。
I sent her poetry.
我送给她一首诗歌
Longfellow.
朗费罗的
Can't go wrong with Longfellow.
朗费罗的诗歌很合适
Day by day I gazed upon her
每天我凝视着她
Day by day I sighed with passion
每天我激情洋溢
Day by day my heart within me
每天在我的心里
Grew more hot with love and longing
生长着更热烈的爱和思慕
I gave her "Hiawatha."
我把她比作是“hiawatha”
All she wanted was a touchdown.
所有她想要的是一个触地得分
Yeah.
是啊
To the quarterback's girlfriend.
敬四分卫的女朋友
To Gloria.
敬凯莱
Drink, drink. It's the best.
喝洒，喝。这是最好的。
- You look terrific.
- Thank you.
-你看起来棒极了
-谢谢
How about some mushroom dip?
来点浸磨菇怎么样？
I thought this was a business meeting.
我认为这是一个商业会议
What's wrong with a little dip?
一点浸磨菇有什么关系？
I never met a person so hard to feed.
我从来没见过一个人这么难养活
Who are you mad at?
你对什么最着迷
Come on, have some dip.
来吧，来些小浸吃。
Swallow.
咽下
Nice.
漂亮
I think we should talk business.
我觉得我们应该谈生意
You have an exquisite neck.
你的脖子很优美
I have to leave by 7.
I have another engagement.
我必须在7点离开，我还有另一个会唔。
Oh, right. I forgot.
哦，好的，我给忘了。
- You got a "proposition."
- Thank you.
-你有一个提议
-谢谢
- Shoot.
- What will it take for you to go away?
-讲吧
-什么会让你走？
Greenmail?
绿票讹诈？
You're offering to buy me out?
你出价买我出局？
Why so uptight? It's not illegal.
为什么这么紧张？这不是违法的。
It's immoral.
这是不道德的。
A distinction that has
no relevance for lawyers.
对律师来说这没什么区别
But it matters to me.
可是这对我很重要
Well, for someone who has
nothing nice to say about lawyers...
嗯，对某些人来说关于律师没什么好说的……
...you certainly have
plenty of them around.
……你当然有很多人围着你转
They're like nuclear warheads.
他们像核弹头
They have theirs, so I have mine.
他们有他们的，所以我有我的
Once you use them,
they fuck up everything.
一旦你使用他们
他们会毁掉一切
Let me ask you:
让我问你：
Do you have authorization
to offer me greenmail?
你有向我绿票讹诈的授权吗？
Of course not.
当然没有
It's a lawyer's scheme.
这是一个律师的方案
Everybody walks out happy.
每个人都皆大欢喜
I get paid off.
我得到回报
Jorgy keeps his company.
jorgy守住了他的公司
The employees keep their jobs.
工人保住了他们的工作
The lawyer gets a big fat fee.
律师得到一大笔佣金
Everybody walks out. Yumpin' yiminy.
皆大欢喜，呀咿
Sounds pretty good to me.
听上去对我非常好。
- Except for the stockholders.
- Their stock falls out of bed...
-除了股东
-他们的股价跌到地板上了……
...they don't know what hit them.
- Now you're Albert Schweitzer.
……他们不知道是什么袭击了他们
-现在你成了史怀哲了
No, not Albert Schweitzer,
Robin Hood.
不，不是史怀哲，是罗宾汉。
I take from the rich,
and I give to the middle class.
我把从富人那里拿来的钱分给中产阶级。
Well, the upper middle class.
嗯，上层中产阶级。
- Would you care for some caviar?
- The stock is 18.
-你要些鱼子酱吗？
-现在的股价是18.
Do you like music? The violin?
你喜欢音乐吗？小提琴的怎么？
- Let's be serious.
- Come on, let's change the subject.
-我们是认真的。
-好吧，我们换个话题吧。
- Arthur.
- The stock is 18. We'll buy it back at 18.
-亚瑟
-现在股价是18美元每股，我们用18美元每股买回来
- First you laugh at me, then you insult me.
- Then name your number.
-开始时你取笑我，现在你又侮辱我
-那告诉我你的数字
- What will you take?
- Twenty-five.
-你想要多少？
-25美元每股
The stock hasn't seen 25 in years.
股价已经没到25几年了。
You want history?
The stock was once 8O.
你想知道历史股价？股价曾经到达过80美元
Take 2O.
20怎么样
Such a high achiever.
很诱人的价格
If you're mad at somebody,
don't take it out on me.
如果你迷上了某人，不要发泄在我身上。
Twenty-five is my number,
and that's a favor.
我出价是25，那是偏爱。
Well, I don't like your number,
and I don't need to be analyzed.
嗯，我不喜欢你的报价，我也不需要分析
Do we have a deal or not?
我们能达成协议吗？
Let's discuss it over dinner.
让我们在晚餐时讨论吧
- Good night. Your 2O minutes are up.
- Wait a minute. I want us to be friends.
-晚安，你的20分钟已经过了
-请稍等，我希望我们能成为朋友。
Let's segue into some soup
and french bread.
让我们继续些汤和法国面包吧
Come on. Don't go away mad.
来吧，不要生气离开
I didn't buy your proposition.
Come back with another one.
我没有买你的主张，回给给我另一个。
You're an emancipated woman.
Learn to lose.
你是一个自由的女人，学会失败
- I haven't lost.
- Wait, wait!
-我没有失败。
-等等
I got a proposition for you.
Hold on, you gotta listen.
我有个建议给你，坚持下去，你一定要听
You come on back up.
你回来
We have a nice dinner.
我们来一个不错的晚餐
We make passionate love
for the rest of the night.
在剩下的夜里，我们可以激情的做爱
The first one who comes, loses.
这第一个来的，是失败一方
- Loses what?
- The deal.
-关于什么失败
-这个协议
I come first, I sell you back
my shares at cost.
我第一个来，我以成本价把我的股份卖还给你
You come first, you buy them at 25.
你第一个来，你出价25美元买回它们
I think you're serious.
我想你是认真的
So how do you suggest
we write this up?
你怎么认为，要我写上吗？
Delicately.
不错
Under the heading,
"Easy come, easy go."
标题写上，“来的容易，去的容易。”
What do you got to lose, your virginity?
I could lose millions.
你会失去什么，你的贞操？
我可以失去数百万。
So, what happens if we come together?
所以，如果我们在一起会发生什么?
I never thought of that.
我从没想过那个
Well...
怎么样……
...think about it, honey.
……考虑一下，亲爱的。
I will. I will.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
我会的，我会的
等等，等等
Come on. Don't go.
来吧，不要走
I haven't played my violin yet.
到现在我还没有拉我的小提琴呢。
Oh, God.
哦，神啊
Hello?
你好?
I just wanted to see if you got home safe.
我只想知道你已经安全到家
Thank you.
谢谢
In your beddy-bye?
你在床上？
I am.
我是
- Did I wake you?
- No.
-我吵醒你了吗
-没
No.
没
- Did you have dinner?
- Yes.
-你吃过晚餐了吗
-是的
With who?
和谁
None of your business.
不关你的事
- Are you thinking about me?
- No.
-你想我了吗？
-没
Well, how could
you possibly manage that?
嗯，怎么可能你可能办到的？
Pills, whiskey, self-help tapes.
丸，威士忌，自助录音带。
I got another proposition for you.
我有另一个建议给你
Oh,  yeah? I can't wait,
听，是吗？我等不及了
We swap.
我们交换
Swap what, dirty jokes?
交换什么，肮脏的笑话吗？
No. I give you all my shares...
不，我给你我所有的股份……
...you give me the wire and cable division.
……你给我电线电缆公司。
Hello?
在吗？
Hello? You like?
在吗，你喜欢吗？
- I'll ask them.
- Good.
-我问一下他们。
-好的
All right, now wait. Don't go away.
Don't hang up. Don't hang up.
好的，先等会，别走开。
别挂线，别挂线。
Stay right where you are. All right.
就呆在你现在呆的地方，好吗
Okay.
好的
Here comes the bridge.
这里是桥
That was very good.
这里非常好
- Thank you.
- You're welcome,
-谢谢
-你是受欢迎的
That was just for you.
那是只为你做的
Well, I appreciate it.
嗯，我很感激
Sweet dreams,
甜蜜的梦
- Okay. Good night.
- Bye-bye.
-好的， 晚安
-再见
Oh, God.
哦，天啊
Forget it.
忘了这吧
Tell him to go to hell.
告诉他去地狱吧
He spends $ 1 3 million for this place...
他在这儿花了13百万……
...then he sells it for 35.
……现在他要卖35百万。
My guys are out of work,
and he's made $ 22 million.
我的人失去了工作
他确赚了22百万
- Now how do I live with that?
- We eliminate a losing division.
-现我我怎么活呢？
-我们消除了一个失败的公司
The other divisions don't have
to support us anymore.
其它公司再也不用支持我们了
- I don't wanna hear that.
- You still control the company.
-我不想听到这些
-你仍然控制公司
- You just don't have the cable division.
- Why is it so difficult...
-你只是没有电线电缆公司
-为什么这样难……
...for everybody to understand...
……让每个人都明白……
...why I can't kill these people
and this town...
……为什么我不能杀了这个镇上的那些人……
...to enrich some son of a bitch
who's trying to destroy me?
……狗娘养的试图靠毁掉我来发财？
I can't play with him
in the courts forever.
我不指望跟他在法庭上玩
He'll get the injunction lifted
and buy more shares.
他会让禁令解除并买更多的股票
Don't be a pigheaded fool.
不要做一个固执的笨蛋了。
He deserves to lose this company.
他理应失去这个公司
- Good night, Mr. Jorgenson.
- Good night, Gus.
-晚安，乔根森先生
-晚安，格斯
Everything going along okay,
Mr. Jorgenson?
一切顺利吗，乔根森先生
Everything's moving right along, Gus.
一切进展顺利，格斯
Everything's gonna be okay,
isn't it, at the plant?
一切还好吗，在这工厂里？
- I mean, at the plant and everything?
- Everything's gonna be just fine.
-我的意思是，在这工厂的里每一件事？
-每件事都不错
We'll be making wire and cable
for a long time.
我们会继续做电线电缆很长一段时间
- Yes, sir. Good night, sir.
- Good night.
-是的，先生，晚安，先生
-晚安
Jorgy?
jorgy?
- Have you got a minute?
- Sure, Bill.
-你有时间吗？
-当然，比尔
Do you mind if I speak frankly
to you, Jorgy?
你介意我跟你坦白说话吗，jorgy?
You always have, haven't you?
你总是，不是吗？
You know...
你知道……
...I'm trained to think in contingency.
……我参加入应急培训。
You know I've spent my life
managing businesses, and...
你知道我花了毕生管理生意，和……
And...
和……
Bill, you're in a panic.
比尔，你有点惊慌。
Well, you know how it is
with business, Jorgy.
嗯，你知道生意的事的，Jorgy
When things don't work out quite right...
当事情不好解决时……
...and people have invested a lot of time,
a lot of their energy, a lot of themselves...
……又当人们在其中投入了很多的时间，投入了很多他们的精力，很多他们自已的……
...management takes care of its own, Jorgy.
It happens all the time.
……管理照顾自已，jorgy.
这是常有的事。
And given the uncertainty
surrounding us these days...
这阵子我我们周边的环境并不确定……
...and the fact that you haven't set up
any financial guarantees for us, Jorgy...
……事实上，你还没有为我们设立任何财务担保，jorgy……
Lord, I hate...
Hate giving this speech.
上帝，我痛恨……
痛恨这样说
When I retire in two years, I've told you,
you're taking over the business.
我告诉过你的，当两年后我将退休，到时你将接手生意。
I promised you that.
我答应过你的
There won't be any business
in two years, Jorgy.
两年后不会有任何生意了，jorgy.
There won't be any business in one year.
一年后也不见得会有生意。
You're holding on to a dream.
那是你的幻想
Go home, Bill. Have a drink.
回家吧，比尔，去喝一杯。
Give my best to Jeanette.
帮我向珍妮问好
I don't want the rug pulled out
from under me so close to the finish line.
我并不想撤出，当离终点线如此的时候
Good night.
晚安
Jorgy, I've been here 1 5 years.
I have a family. Something's due me.
我已经在这里15年了，我有一个家，我还期望有所得呢
Now, I've worked my ass off
for 1 5 years...
现在，你在这个位置坐了15年……
...and you're gonna let that man come in
and take over the company. It's not right.
……你确要让那个人参于进来并接管公司，这不对。
I'm sorry, Bill.
抱歉，比尔。
Up here we don't plan the funeral
until the body is dead.
我不打算在这举行葬礼，直到我死了。
Sounds like everybody's hungry.
看上去每个都很饿。
Well, let's eat.
好吧，让我的开动吧
- Sit down, darling.
- Happy Thanksgiving.
-请坐，亲受的。
-感恩节快乐
Thank thee, Father, for thy care,
for thy bounty everywhere.
感谢你，主，感谢你的关怀，你的慷慨无处不在
For this and every other gift,
our grateful hearts to thee we lift.
真诚的感激主所赋我们这以及所有其它礼物
Amen.
啊门
Second down and 1 O, Lions at their 49,
在10码处第二次进攻，狮子队在49的位置，
I don't know why you watch this.
It's so stupid!
我不知道为什么你会看这么，看上去很愚蠢！
Maybe if you'd watch, you'd see.
See, he's going right now.
如何你在看的话，你会看到，看，他正往前冲
Yes. Go, go, go!
好，冲，冲，冲！
I told you.
My money was on Detroit.
告诉你，我在底特律队上压了钱
Have to admit,
we still have fresh air up here.
必须承认，我们在这里仍然有新鲜空气。
Feels good, all right.
感觉很好
I'm awfully glad you came, Kate.
我很高兴你来了，凯特
It means a hell of a lot to your mother.
对你母亲来说，这意味着很多
I love your mother.
你爱你母亲
I can't say I'm sorry for that,
but I am sorry for whatever it is...
我不能不说我我很抱歉，我很抱歉不管他是什么……
...that it's done to you
in the last 21 - Odd years.
……在过去的21年对你所做的
I'm okay, Jorgy.
我很好，jorgy.
Good.
好的
Now let's talk a little business.
现在我们谈点生意上的事。
Let's quit talking about what I won't do.
我们不要讨论我不会做什么。
Let's talk about what I will do.
让我们讨论一下我将要做什么。
I have a problem.
我遇到麻烦了
I'm a good lawyer.
I'm a lousy mind reader.
我是个好律师。
我是一个只会出瘦主意的人。
I wanna put it to a vote.
Annual meeting in four weeks.
我想在四周后的年度会议上进行投票决议
Wanna put it in the hands
of the stockholders.
想让公司的股东进行表决
Can't do that. It's too risky.
We could lose everything.
不能那样做，太危险了，我会会失去一切的。
- You're a fighter. I'm a fighter.
- It's too dangerous.
-你是一个战士，我是一个战士。
-太危险了
There's no other choice
that I can live with.
我没有其他选择
This 3O percent,
this faithful 3O percent...
30%股份，忠实的30%股份……
...can you absolutely count on them?
……你可以绝对的相信他们？
They haven't let me down so far.
到目前为止他们还没有让我失望过。
Awful lot of Ozzies on our side.
很多像奥齐那样的人支持我们
Don't trust Ozzie. He's a banker.
不要相信奥齐，他是个银行家。
I have to trust my friends, Kate.
我不得不信任我的朋友，凯特。
This is gonna be tough.
这将是棘手的。
I have to get Garfield to buy this.
我已经让加菲尔德买这个了。
He won't want to.
It's not to his advantage.
他不想要的，这不是他的优势。
Talk nice.
很好的谈话
Give him your best smile.
给他最好的笑容
Come on, Kate.
加油，凯特
Let's take on the little son of a bitch.
让我们把这个狗娘养的，
Let's kick his ass
all the way back to Wall Street.
把他们踢回到华尔街去
It's a quiet place.
这是一个安静的地方
I thought it would be a good idea
if we calmed down a bit.
我认为我们冷静一点是个好主意
Do you like Japanese?
你喜欢日本吗？
I'd like to have Sony.
我喜欢索尼产品
Could you bring me a knife and fork?
你能给我拿刀和叉吗？
So, what do you say?
所以，你觉得怎么样？
A proxy fight? I'd have to be nuts.
代理战？我会疯的
I could sit on my ass and wait
for the injunction to lift...
我会坐下来等禁令解除……
...buy all the shares I need.
……买入所有我需要的股票。
Anybody else,
I wouldn't even come to lunch.
我不想其它任何人来分一杯羹
You look very nice today.
你今天看起来非常漂亮
But if you win, Lawrence,
it speeds up the process.
所以如果你雇员了，劳伦斯，就加快了进程。
You get what you want in three months
instead of a year, maybe two.
在这三个月内你会得到你想要的，而不是一年，也许二年。
I love it when you call me Lawrence.
我喜欢你叫我劳伦斯
Say it again.
再说一次
There's a lot can stand
in your way, Lawrence.
你会遇上很多阻碍，劳伦斯
Anti-takeover legislation's
in the works.
现在有反收购立法
Drexel's gone under. Milken's in jail.
德崇垮了，米尔肯现在在监狱里。
Trump's waiting tables.
川普正在被传唤
Don't threaten me.
不要恐吓我
And just maybe you're over-leveraged,
and you can't afford to wait.
也许你正在负债中，所以你不能等
- Thank you. You got any bread?
- No bread.
-谢谢，你有任何面包类的东西吗？
-没有面包
No bread.
没面包
They got no bread.
他们不吃面包
They wanna run the world,
they got no bread.
他们想统治世界，可他们不吃面包。
In three weeks, you present your own slate.
If you win, you buy everybody out at 2O.
三个星期内，你提交你的预案，
如果你赢了，我们以每股20元卖给你。
If you lose, you sell us back
your shares at 1 5.
如果你输了，我们以15元每股买回你的份额
Worst-case scenario,
you still make a couple million.
最坏的情况，你仍然挣好几个百万
Amazing people, the Japanese.
日本人是令人惊讶的民族
We blow the hell out of them.
我们用核弹炸了他们
They go back to school, learn English
and start to run the world.
他们回到学校，开始学英语并准备统治世界
What do we do?
我们做了什么?
We get bigheaded,
start living the good life.
我们自大的过着美好的生活。
Forget about schools.
没有学校
People can't read. People can't write.
人不能读，不能写
Country's full of dropouts.
全国满是辍学者
Education.
教育
Who needs education as long
as you can blow up the world?
要炸掉整个世界的人才需要教育？
Meanwhile, I got everybody
in my office learning Japanese.
这意味着，我要办公室的每个人都学习日语
I've never seen such a beautiful lawyer.
我还没有见过这么漂亮的律师
Come on, Lawrence.
来吧，劳伦斯
This is your game.
这是你的游戏
Winner takes all.
赢家通吃
Rumor has it, you got balls.
有传言说，你得到球了
I've been trying to show you for weeks.
这几个星期我一直想告诉你
Well, here's your opportunity.
嗯，现在你有机会了。
All right.
好的
I can always use
a good proxy bloodbath.
我随时可以使用一个很好的代理屠杀。
After all, I wanna give you
a fighting chance.
毕竟，我想给你一个战斗的机会
I love you.
我爱你
Of course you do.
你当然
Because we're the same.
因为我们是同一类人
We are not the same, Lawrence.
我们是不一样的，劳伦斯
Now, don't go spreading that around.
所以现在，不要这样去别跟人讲
You know what makes us the same...
你知道我们在哪一样……
...what sets us apart?
……哪里不一样？
We care more about the game
than we do the players.
我们都关心这场游戏甚于做选手
Oh, is that so?
哦，是这样吗？
Yeah...
是的……
...that's so.
……就是那样
I'm gonna nail you, Lawrence...
我要抓住你……，劳伦斯
...and everybody
on Wall Street's gonna know...
……华尔街上的每个人都将知道……
...some broad did you in.
……一些你不为人知的一面
You're so perfect for me.
你太抬举我了
- I have to go.
- Don't go.
-我必须走了
-不要走
Lunch is on me, baby-poo.
午餐很合我意，宝贝
Where you going?
你要去哪？
I have to go back to the office.
我要回办公室
Don't go back to the office.
Come and work for me.
不要回去办公室，来为我工作。
Lady said to say, "We have no doughnuts."
那女士要我告诉你，“我们没有甜甜圈。”
Here's your coffee, boss.
老板，这是你的咖啡
You make me feel like a dirty crook.
你使我感觉像一个肮脏的骗子
Sneaking off to Jersey is not my style.
偷偷去新泽西不是我的风格
Can we speak frankly?
我可以坦率的说吗？
No. Lie to me.
不，骗我吧
Tell me how thrilled you are
to know me.
告诉我你有多兴奋认识我
I always speak frankly. I hate people
who say, "Can we speak frankly?"
我总是说的很坦率，我恨别人说，“我可以坦率地说吗？”
It means they're bullshitting me
the rest of the time.
这意味着在剩下的时间里他们在蒙我
I'm listening.
我在听
Now...
现在……
...as you know, I had 8O, OOO shares
of New England stock when we first met.
……你知道，当我们第一次见面的时候我持有8万股新英格兰电线电缆的股份
What am I getting, a history lesson here?
Get to the point.
我得到什么，历史课？讲重点
Since becoming aware
of your investments...
自从意识到你在投资……
...I bought an additional 4O, OOO shares.
I now have 1 OO, OOO shares.
……我又增持了4万股份。我现在有10万个份额了
Congratulations.
恭喜
I'm prepared...
我准备……
...to sell you the right...
……卖给你权利……
...to vote those shares
at the annual meeting.
……在年度会议上投票
How much?
多少钱
- A million.
- Too much.
-一百万
-太多了
You need a million shares
more than you already own.
你需要更多的一百万股比你已经拥有的
Now, I can get you 1 O percent
of the way there in one transaction.
现在，只要一个交易你能得到10%的份额
Better still, it's votes
they're counting on for themselves.
更好的是，他们依靠自己的股份投票
They lose 1 O percent,
you gain 1 O percent.
他们失去10%，你就获得10%
If you make a difference...
如果你到时变卦……
...if I win by less than 1 OO, OOO votes,
you got your million.
……或如果我没用到这10万的选票就赢了，你就挣了一百万了。
Otherwise, I don't need them,
I won't vote them.
另外，我不需要它们，我不会投票
I'm not selling you an option.
我不是卖给你一个选择
I'm selling you the right
to vote the shares.
我是卖给你这些股票的投票权利
If they make a difference,
you got a million.
如果他们不干了，你就挣了一百万美元
If they don't, half a million.
如果他们不干了，半百万
I've prepared the papers.
我准备好的文件
Left the numbers blank.
You can have your lawyers look at them.
除了数据是空白的，你可以让你的律师看看
Everybody looks out for their own
self-interest, don't they?
每个人都顾自己的利益，不是吗？
"What's in it for me?"
Isn't that what it's finally all about?
“我有什么好处？”这是不是所有事情的最终方式？
Yes. Very good. Very good.
可以，完成的不错，非常不错
- When do we run in the Times?
- Tomorrow.
-什么时候登在泰晤士报上
-明天
- Times, Barron's, Forbes...
- Boston Herald.
-泰晤士，巴伦，福布斯……
-波士顿先驱报
- Next week, major cities in New England.
- Great.
-下周，在新英格兰的主要城市
-太好了
Take this copy and slide it
all over to the right.
把所有这些备份都标上所属
And up in the corner here,
put that picture of me.
在这上面的角落里放我的照片
- You know?
- You look good in that shot.
-你知道吗？
-这样你会看上去很不错
Oh, God. Look at him.
听，上帝，看看他
He's trying to look like Desmond Tutu.
他想让自己看起来像德斯蒙德
All right, Richard, get our ad agency.
好了，李察，找我们的广告代理
- Call Barbaro. Call Pinelli.
- Barbaro,  Pinelli.
-打电话给巴巴罗，派尼。
-芒派，尼里
- Yeah. Where's that phone call from Tokyo?
- I'm on it,
-是的，这是从东京打来的电话吗？
-我来着手处理
Taxi. Taxi!
出租车
Thanks, Ron.
谢谢，荣恩
Mr. Garfield's office.
加菲尔德先生的办公室
I expect him back at 5:3O.
Thanks, Connie.
我希望他能在5:30回来
谢谢，康妮
I'll ask him to phone you.
Bye-bye.
我会叫他给你打电话
再见
Look, I found it. I found it.
看，我找到它了，我找到它了
Mrs. Sullivan. She insisted
on waiting for you.
沙利文夫人，她坚持在等你
I would appreciate a few moments
of your time.
我可以占用你的一点时间吗
Certainly.
Hey, come on in the office.
当然
嘿，来我的办公室吧
- Hold my calls.
- Will do.
-帮我接电话
-我会的
Come on in. Have a seat right there.
进来吧，在这坐
Did your daughter send you?
Because she's full of clever moves.
是你女儿让你来的？因为她充满了聪明的行动
No, she didn't. She would be
very upset with me if she knew.
不，没有，如果她知道驰会非常生气
I like Kate. She's quite the tomato.
我喜欢凯特，她很可人
She must have taken after you, huh?
她一定是学你的，嗯？
You're very kind.
你很亲切
I would hope this meeting
will be held in confidence.
我希望这次的会议是私下的
Everybody's looking
for confidence these days.
这些天，每个人都想私下的谈
You want a cup of coffee?
你要一杯咖啡吗？
- Cup of tea? Glass of water?
- You needn't be sociable, Mr. Garfield.
-一杯茶？或一杯水？
-你不必是交际的，加菲尔德先生
- Harriet, cup of coffee.
- Yes.
-哈丽特，一杯咖啡
-是的
You mind if I smoke?
你介意我吸烟吗？
I'd like to tell you why I'm here.
我想告诉你我为什么在这里
Good. Shoot.
好的，说吧
I'm here to plead for our company.
我在这里为我的公司恳求
I want to talk to you
about hopes and dreams...
我想和你谈谈关于希望和梦想……
...traditions.
……传统的。
Would you care for a doughnut,
Mrs. Sullivan?
你要一个甜甜圈吗？沙利文太太
We've worked so hard
to build this company.
为建设这个公司我们工作很努力
We're debt-free...
我不没有债务……
...and we don't deserve to lose it.
……我们不应该失去它
I want you to call off your fight with us.
我想让我们的斗争结束
There's a trust fund in my name
with a million dollars in it.
在我的名义下有一个信托基金，里面有一百万美元
I'll turn it over to you if you go away.
如果你离开，我就把它交给你
You don't wanna do that.
你不想那么做的
We'll buy back your shares at cost,
plus you'll have a million dollars profit.
我们会用成本价买回你手中的股票，加入你将获得一百万美元的利润
Interesting.
有意思
I know a million dollars
isn't much money to you...
我知道一百万美元对你来说不是很多……
...but if I had more, I'd give it to you.
……但如果我有更多，我都会给你
Who are you doing it for?
你这样做是为了谁？
Money's not that important to me.
钱对我来说并不是很重要
- Well, it is to me.
- Then accept my offer.
-咽，我看重它
-那接受我的提议
You'll have more money
than most people make in a lifetime.
你会有更多的钱比大多数人的一辈子
A million dollars.
一百万美元
It's not enough.
这不够
Go home, Mrs. Sullivan.
回去吧，沙利文夫人
I'd hoped to appeal
to your sense of decency.
我希望唤醒你的良知
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I don't take money from widows
or orphans. I make them money.
我不从寡妇和狐儿那挣钱，我为他们挣钱
Before or after you put them out
of business?
让他们从生意中出局之前还是之后？
What a woman.
什么样的女人
Harriet, why do I always bring out
the best in people?
哈丽特，为什么我总是拿出最出的一面亲民
Hello?
您好？
Oh, please,
哦，拜托！
Arthur!
亚瑟！
Get the car. Arthur.
去取车，亚瑟
I'm sorry, sir. There's no answer
in Miss Sullivan's apartment.
先生，抱歉，沙利文小姐的公寓没有回复
Well, try it again.
Maybe you dialed it wrong.
嗯，再试一次，可能你拨错号了
No!
不
Excuse me, Bart.
What are you doing here?
请原谅，巴特
你在这干什么？
- Who's Bart?
- I'm on my way out. You should've called.
-巴特是谁?
-我正要出去，你应事先来电话的
- I need to talk to you.
- I don't have time...
-我需要和你谈谈
-我没时间了……
I have something important to tell you.
I need to talk now.
我有些重要的事要告诉你
我需要现在就说
- You look beautiful. Who's this guy?
- Excuse me, Lawrence. Call me tomorrow.
-你看上去真漂亮，那个家伙是谁?
-抱歉，劳伦斯，明天给我电话
I can't talk tomorrow. It won't keep.
我不能等到明天谈
I want you to marry me.
我要你嫁给我
Let me put it another way.
换句庆说
I wanna marry you.
我想取你
You thinking it over?
你考虑过吗？
- What are you talking about?
- What do you mean?
-你在说什么？
-你什么意思？
I want you to be my wife.
We belong together.
我想你成为我的妻子
我们属于一起
- I'm going to the opera. I gotta go.
- No, no, Kate.
-我正要去歌剧院，我要走了
-不，不，凯特
You're the last thought I have
when I fall asleep at night...
你是我入睡时最后想念的人……
...and the first when I wake up
in the morning.
……和早上醒来最先想念的人
I wanna be with you forever and ever.
我想和你永远在一起
I wanna have babies with you.
我想和生孩子
- Babies?
- Yeah.
-孩子？
-是的
You see, I gotta do this now,
because after I win...
你看，我得现在这么做，因为在我赢了后……
...maybe you won't wanna speak to me.
- You can't win. I'm gonna win.
……也许你不会想跟我说话了。
-你不能赢，我要赢。
I know how important it is to you,
but you're not gonna win.
我知道它对你有多重要，但你不会赢
This is what's killing me.
这个对来我说很要命
I want you. I need you. I love you.
I just don't wanna lose you.
我想你，我需要你，我爱你
我只是不想失去你
- Katherine.
- Keep your pants on, will you, Bart?
-凯瑟琳
-镇定，你会吧，巴特？
- I've gotta go.
- All right, the opera. La Traviata.
-我得走了
-好，歌剧，茶花女
You don't wanna miss the first act.
It sets up the whole thing.
你不想错过第一幕
你建立了整个事情
It's a wonderful production.
这是一个好作品
Have a good time.
玩的高兴
I'm gonna lose her, Arthur.
亚瑟，我会失去她的
Oh, I've been looking for you.
哦，我一直在找你
Anytime you're ready.
只要你准备好
You okay?
你还好吗？
Yeah.
是的
Just going over in my mind
what I wanna say.
我正在构思我要说什么
They're putting speakers outside.
他们正把音箱放在外面
I think every shareholder
within driving distance is coming.
我认为每一个在开车距离内的股东都会来
I feel as if we're Harry and Bess
on election night.
我觉得我们就像选举之夜时的哈里和贝丝
Harry Truman was a better man than me.
He slept on election night.
哈里・杜鲁门比我强
他能在大选之夜睡着
I haven't slept in days.
我几天没睡好了
Talk to me. Tell me.
跟我谈谈，告诉我
I'm scared.
我害怕
I'm scared that...
我害怕……
...time has passed us by.
……时间从我们身边流逝
I'm scared I don't know
this new environment.
我害怕我不认识这个新环境
I'm scared that what I do know
doesn't count for anything anymore.
我害怕我知道这不算什么
Things have changed.
事情已经改变了
Whatever happened
to people serving each other?
无论和这些共患难的人之间发生了什么？
I don't want this man to win.
我不想这个人赢
I'm not scared.
我不害怕
I'm just proud.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of the business we've built.
我为我们已经建立的业务骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
我为你骄傲
And if what we are
counts for nothing anymore...
如果我们不是什么了……
...then that's their failing, not ours.
……那是他们的失败，不是我们。
It'll be all right.
它会没事的
Just go out and tell the truth.
只要走出去，并告诉真相
Go out and give them hell, Harry.
出去给他们一击，哈利。
Good luck to us all today, Bill.
今天祝我们所有人好运，比尔。
I feel we're gonna be just fine.
我觉得我们会好的
Looks like they've come from everywhere.
New York, Boston.
看来他们来自各处。纽约，波士顿。
- There's Ozzie.
- Happening all over, isn't it?
-那是奥兹
-发生了，不是吗？
Everybody looking out for themselves.
每个人都在为他们自己
So did you get
your golden parachute, Bill?
所以你得到了你的金色降落伞了，比尔？
Did he finally promise to take care of you?
他最终答应照顾你了？
Lord of the manor, house on the hill.
在山上房子的庄园主
Said he didn't want to talk about a funeral
while there was no corpse.
说他不想谈没有尸体的葬礼
Well, time to go.
好了，是走的时候了
Bill.
比尔
How you gonna vote?
你要如何投票？
Oh, boy. They're out in droves, Arthur.
They got the kids here.
哦，伙记。他们正成群结队的，亚瑟。
他们把孩子带到这儿来了
Why do they always bring the kids,
Arthur?
为什么他们总是把孩子带过来,亚瑟？
That's right. Hooray, hooray.
Down with Garfield.
对哦，万岁，万岁，打倒加菲尔德
Okay, TV crews.
好了，电视工作人员
Financial News Network, here we come.
财经新闻网，我来了
Mr. Garfield!
加菲尔德！
What are your plans
for New England Wire and Cable?
你怎么计划新英格兰电线电缆公司？
Make the stockholders richer.
让股东挣变得更富裕
Will you liquidate New England Wire and
Cable? And if so, what about the workers?
你会解散新英格兰电线电缆公司吗？如果会，那工人怎么办？
My obligation is to the stockholders.
The board of directors make that decision.
我对股东负责。
董事会会做出决定
Oh, come on!
噢，得了吧！
What about the workers?
工人怎么办？
Are they gonna lose their jobs?
Come on, answer the question.
他们会失去他们的工作吗？来吧，回答这个问题
Come on, Mr. Garfield!
来吧，加菲尔德！
How do you feel about the outcome
of today's proxy vote?
你觉得今天的代理投票会有怎样的结果？
I feel confident that the shareholders
will vote their consciences.
我深信，股东会凭良知投票的
I have every confidence
in this company's future.
我对公司的未来很有信心
Could I have your attention, please?
请大家安静一下？
Welcome to...
欢迎光临……
...New England Wire and Cable's
annual stockholders' meeting.
……新英格兰电线电缆年度股东大会
I'm William J. Coles, your president,
and I'm sure...
我是威廉・科尔斯，你们的总经理，我肯定……
I'm sure that everyone here realizes
the most important item on the agenda...
我确信在这里的每个人实现最重要的一项议程……
...is the election
of the board of directors.
……是选举公司的董事
Now, there are staff members
passing out the ballots.
现在，工作人员在发选票
Right now, I am very proud
to introduce to you...
现在，我很自豪地向你们介绍……
...a man who could accurately
be characterized as a legend...
准备的说，一个有传奇色彩的人……
...in the wire and cable industry.
……在电线电缆行业
The chairman of the board
of New England Wire and Cable...
新英格兰电线电缆公司的董事会主席……
...Mr. Andrew Jorgenson.
……安得烈・乔根森先生
Give them hell, Andy!
安迪，让他们见鬼去吧
It's good to see so many...
很高兴看到这么多……
...familiar faces, so many old friends.
……熟悉的面孔，这么多老朋友
Some of you I haven't seen in years.
你们有些人我很久没见过了
Thank you for coming.
谢谢你的光临
Bill Coles, our able president,
in the annual report, has told you...
比尔科尔斯，我们的总经理，在年度报告中，已经告诉你……
...of our year, of what we accomplished,
of the need for further improvements...
……这一年我们所完成的，及需要做进一步改进的……
...our business goals for next year
and the years beyond.
……我们企业明年的目标和多年以后的
I'd like to talk to you
about something else.
我想和你们谈谈其它事情
I want to share with you
some of my thoughts...
我想和你们分享我的一些想法……
...concerning the vote that you're going
to make in the company that you own.
……关于你们将要投票的你们自己的公司
This proud company, which has survived
the death of its founder,,,
这个令人骄傲的公司，依然幸存，历经创始人去世、
,,, numerous recessions,
one major depression and two world wars,,,
……众多次衰退，一次大萧条和两次世界大战……
,,, is in imminent danger
of self-destructing,
……现在却正面临自我毁灭的威胁
On this day, in the town of its birth,
就在今天，就在这座它诞生的小镇
There is the instrument
of our destruction.
这就是要解散我们公司的家伙
I want you to look at him in all of his glory.
"Larry the Liquidator."
我想你们看看他，及他所有的荣耀
“清算人拉里”
The entrepreneur of post-industrial America
playing God...
后工业时代美国的企业家扮演着上帝……
...with other people's money.
……用别人的钱
The robber barons of old at least
left something tangible in their wake.
即使是旧时代的强盗大亨在他们身后也会留下一些可触摸的东西
A coal mine, a railroad, banks.
一个煤矿，铁路，银行
This man leaves nothing.
这个人什么也没留下
He creates nothing.
He builds nothing.
他什么也没创造
他什么也不建造
He runs nothing.
他什么也不经营
And in his wake lies nothing
but a blizzard of paper to cover the pain.
在他后，什么也不会留下，除了带来灾难的成堆文件
Oh, if he said, "I know how to run
your business better than you"...
哦，如果他说，“我知道如何把生意做的比你更好……”
...that would be something
worth talking about...
……那还值得谈谈……
...but he's not saying that.
……但他并没有那样说
He's saying, "I'm gonna kill you
because at this particular moment in time...
他说“我会杀了你，因为在这个特定的时刻……
...you're worth more dead than alive."
……你死了比活着更值钱。”
Well...
好吧……
...maybe that's true, but it is also true...
……可能那是事实，但是这也是真的
...that one day this industry will turn.
……就是会有一天这个行业会走好。
One day when the yen is weaker,
the dollar is stronger...
当日元疲软，美元走强的那一天……
...or when we finally begin
to rebuild our roads, our bridges...
……或当我们开始重建我们的道路，桥梁……
...the infrastructure of our country,
demand will skyrocket.
……我国的基础设施，需求会激增
And when those things happen,
we will still be here...
当这些发生时，我们仍然会在这里……
...stronger because of our ordeal,
stronger because we have survived.
……更强壮因为经历为考验，
更强壮因为我们存活了下来。
And the price of our stock
will make his offer pale by comparison.
我们股票到时价格走高，会让他现在的收购价相形失色
God save us if we vote to take
his paltry few dollars and run.
上帝会拯救我们，如果我们投票决定注入一些小资金让其运行
God save this country
if that is truly the wave of the future.
上帝会拯救这个国家如果这确实是未来的浪潮
We will then have become a nation
that makes nothing but hamburgers...
我们将会成一个专做汉堡的的民族……
...creates nothing but lawyers
and sells nothing but tax shelters.
……一无所造除了律师，一无所卖除了避税避税服务
And if we are at that point in this country
where we kill something...
如果我们在这个点，在这个国家杀死什么……
...because at the moment
it's worth more dead than alive...
就因为此刻死比活值得更多……
...well...
……好吧
...take a look around. Look at your
neighbor. Look at your neighbor.
……看看周围，看看你的邻居
You won't kill him, will you? No.
你不会杀死他，对吧？你不会
It's called murder, and it's illegal.
这被称作是谋杀，并且这也是非法的
Well, this, too, is murder,
on a mass scale.
嗯，这，也是谋杀，一个大规模的
Only on Wall Street,
they call it maximizing shareholder value...
只有在华尔街，
他们称它为股东价值最大化……
...and they call it legal.
……他们称它是合法的。
And they substitute dollar bills
where a conscience should be.
他们用美元钞票取代了良心的位置
Damn it!
该死！
A business is worth more
than the price of its stock.
业务运营比其股价更具价值
It's the place where we earn our living,
where we meet our friends...
这是我们谋生和会见朋友的地方……
...dream our dreams.
……梦想我们的梦想
It is, in every sense, the very fabric
that binds our society together.
它是，从每个意义上，是我们社会紧密连接在一起的构造
So let us now, at this meeting...
所以让我们现在，在这次会议上……
...say to every Garfield in the land...
……对这片土地上的每一个加菲尔德说……
...here, we build things,
we don't destroy them.
……在这里，我们建立事物，我们不毁灭他们
Here, we care about more
than the price of our stock.
在这里，比起股票价格我们在乎更多的东西
Here...
在这里……
...we care about people.
……我们在乎人
Thank you.
谢谢
And now I'd like to introduce
Mr. Lawrence Garfield.
现在我想介绍劳伦斯加菲尔德先生
Mr. Gar...
Excuse... Please.
加……   对不起，等一下
Let's show a little courtesy,
ladies and gentlemen.
让我们表现出一点礼貌，女士们，先生们。
Mr. Garfield is the president
and the chairman of the board...
加菲尔德是总经理和委员会主席……
...of Garfield Investments.
……加菲尔投资公司
Mr. Garfield.
加菲尔德先生
Amen.
阿门
And amen.
You have to forgive me.
I'm not familiar with the local custom.
你必须原谅我，我不熟悉当地的风俗
Where I come from, you always say amen
after you hear a prayer.
我来的那个地方，当你听完祷告后你总是说阿门
Because that's what you just heard.
那是因为你刚听到的
A prayer.
一个祈祷者
Where I come from...
我从那里来……
...that particular prayer
is called the prayer for the dead.
……那个特别的祈祷被称为“为死祈祷”
You just heard the prayer for the dead,
my fellow stockholders...
你刚听到了为死亡的祈祷，各位股东……
...and you didn't say amen.
……你没有说阿门
This company is dead.
这个公司死了
I didn't kill it. Don't blame me.
我没有杀它，不要责怪我
It was dead when I got here.
当我到这里的时候，它已经死了
It's too late for prayers.
作祈祷太晚了
For even if the prayers were answered
and a miracle occurred...
甚至如果祈祷有回应，那奇迹就发生了……
...and the yen did this
and the dollar did that...
……日元这样，美元那样……
...and the infrastructure did the other thing,
we would still be dead.
……和基础设施的其他东西，象刚才所说那样
我们仍然会死。
You know why?
你知道为什么吗？
Fiber optics.
纤维光学
New technologies.
新技术
Obsolescence.
过时了
We're dead, all right.
我们已经死了，那不要紧
We're just not broke.
我们并没有破产
And do you know the surest way
to go broke?
你知道怎么样会走向破产吗？
Keep getting an increasing share
of a shrinking market.
在市场萎缩的时候保持增加持股
Down the tubes.
走下坡
Slow but sure.
缓慢，但肯定
You know, at one time...
你知道，在同一时间……
...there must have been dozens
of companies making buggy whips.
……这儿曾经肯定有很多制作马车的公司
And I'll bet the last company around
was the one that made...
我敢打赌这最后一家公司，是一个……
...the best goddamn buggy whip
you ever saw.
……你所看到的做最好的该死的马车鞭子的
Now, how would you have liked to have
been a stockholder in that company?
现在，如果你是那个公司的股东你会怎么想
You invested in a business,
and this business is dead.
你一个生意中投了钱，但这个生意已经死了
Let's have the intelligence,
let's have the decency...
让我们有智慧
让我们有尊严……
...to sign the death certificate,
collect the insurance...
签署死亡证明……
收取保险费……
...and invest in something with a future.
……或投资其它有前途的事
"But we can't," goes the prayer.
“我们不能，”祈祷者说
We can't, because
we have a responsibility...
我们不能，因为我们有责任……
...a responsibility to our employees,
to our community.
对员工、对我们的社区负责
What will happen to them?
他们将会发生什么？
I got two words for that:
关于这，我有两个字：
Who cares?
谁关心？
Care about them? Why?
关心他们？为什么？
They didn't care about you.
他们不关心你
They sucked you dry.
你们榨干你
You have no responsibility to them.
你对他们没有责任
For the last 1 O years,
this company bled your money.
在过去的10年里
这公司榨取你的钱
Did this community ever say,
"We know times are tough.
这个社区曾是否说“我们知道日子难过，
We'll lower taxes,
reduce water and sewer"?
我们会降低税收，减少排污费？
Check it out. You're paying
twice what you did 1 O years ago.
查查看，你的支出是10年前的两倍
And our devoted employees who have taken
no increases for the past three years...
我们深爱的员工在过去的三年中收入并没有增加……
...are still making twice
what they made 1 O years ago.
而做出的产出却是10年前的两倍
And our stock,
one-sixth what it was 1 O years ago.
我们的股价，10年前的价格就是16美元每股
Who cares?
谁关心？
I'll tell you.
我来告诉你
Me.
我
I'm not your best friend.
我不是你最好的朋友
I'm your only friend.
我是你唯一的朋友
I don't make anything?
我什么也不做
I'm making you money.
我为你生钱
And lest we forget,
that's the only reason...
不要忘记，就是我们唯一的原因……
...any of you became stockholders
in the first place.
……你们中的任何一个人在成为股东的第一个地方
You want to make money.
你想赚钱
You don't care if they manufacture wire
and cable, fried chicken or grow tangerines!
你不在乎他们生产电线电缆的，炸鸡肉的或种桔子的！
You wanna make money!
你想赚钱！
I'm the only friend you've got.
I'm making you money.
我是你唯一的朋友
我为你挣钱
Take the money.
拿着这些钱
Invest it somewhere else.
把它投资到其它地方
Maybe...
也许……
Maybe you'll get lucky,
and it'll be used productively.
如果你够幸运，它被富有成效地使用了
And if it is, you'll create new jobs
and provide a service for the economy...
如是是这样，你会创造新的工作并为经济提供了服务……
...and, God forbid,
even make a few bucks for yourselves.
然后，上帝保佑
甚至为你自己挣了一大笔钱。
And if anybody asks,
tell them you gave at the plant.
如果有人问，告诉他们这是你工厂的分红
And by the way...
顺便说一下……
...it pleases me that I am called
"Larry the Liquidator."
……我很高兴被称作“拉里清算人。”
You know why, fellow stockholders?
你知道为什么吗，各位股东？
Because at my funeral...
因为在我的葬礼……
...you'll leave with a smile on your face
and a few bucks in your pocket.
你会带着笑容和你口袋中的美元离开
Now, that's a funeral worth having.
现在，这是一个划算的葬礼
The ballots will be marked...
选票将被标记……
...and deposited in the ballot boxes
at the rear of the hall. Thank you.
……和存放在大厅后部的投票箱里，谢谢
Ladies and gentlemen, please.
各位，请
May I have your attention, please?
请大家注意一下？
I will now read
the results of the balloting.
我现在读投票结果
To retain the present board:
董事会保有票：
1,741, 418.
1，741，418.
For the opposition: 2,21 9,9O1.
反对投票：2，219，901.
Not voting: 1 78, 111.
弃权票：178，111.
Mr. Garfield, your slate is elected.
加菲尔德先生，你的议案被选中了
Congratulations, Mr. Garfield.
祝贺你，加菲尔德先生
Congratulations, Lawrence.
祝贺你，劳伦斯
You okay, boss?
你还好吧，老板？
You want some chicken soup
or something?
你想要鸡汤还是什么？
No.
不。
Pie?
馅饼？
No.
不。
How about some of that carrot cake
you like so much?
你喜欢的胡萝卜蛋糕怎么样
No.
不。
Well, Carmen, we did it again.
好的，卡门，我们又做成了
I can always count on you, can't I?
我总是可以信赖你，是吗？
Another barrelful of money.
另一个大量的钱
Not bad for a kid from the Bronx.
对一个从布朗士来的人说很不错
I love money.
我爱钱
Mr, Garfield,  Kate Sullivan is on the line,
加菲尔德先生，凯特沙丽文的电话，
Are you in or out,  Mr, Garfield?
你在吗，加菲尔德先生
- Hello?
- You're a greedy, arrogant, self-absorbed...
-你好？
-你是个贪婪，傲慢，自大……
- ,,, overbearing...
- Avaricious?
-……专横的……
-贪财的？
I have a proposition for you,
我有个提议给你
Are you ready, Lawrence?
准备好了吗，劳伦斯？
Ready,
准备好了
Air bags.
安全气囊
Air bags?
安全气囊？
Every car in America
is about to have one,
在美国的每辆车都将装一个
Did you know that air bags
are made from stainless-steel wire cloth?
你知道吗，安全气囊是由不锈钢丝的布做成的吗？
Did you dump Bart?
你把巴特甩了吗？
The Mitsushimi Company of Japan
is ready to make a long-term deal...
日本的三凌公司准备做一个长期合同……
...with New England Wire and Cable...
……新英格兰电线电缆公司……
,,, for the production of air bags,
……生产安全气囊，
I love the sound of your voice.
我喜欢听你的声音
Well,  here comes the best part,
Lawrence,
嗯，现在这里是最好的部分，劳伦斯，
You sell Wire and Cable
back to the employees.
你把电线电缆公司卖回给员工
They modernize and re-equip the plant
and turn out air bags.
他们把工厂的设备做一个现代化地改造并生产安全气囊
What's in it for me?
我有什么好处?
They'll pay 28 bucks a share,
他们将支付28美元一股
You like?
你喜欢吗？
They'll go to 3O.
股价会到30的
Thirty? You think so?
30？你这么想？
Why not? We'll talk about it at dinner.
I'll see you in an hour.
为什么不，我将在晚晚餐时跟你讨论。
我会在一个小时后看到你
Lunch, tomorrow, 1: OO.
午餐，明天，1点
You know where. Strictly business.
你知道地方的，纯脆的生意会晤
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. Strictly business.
哦，是，是，是，纯脆的生意会晤
Wow, did you hear that, Carmen?
哇哦，你听到了吗，卡门？
Harriet! Call my manicurist,
call the barber, call the florist...
哈丽特，打电话给我的美甲师，理发师，打电话给花店……
...tell Arthur I want two tickets
to the opera tomorrow night. Puccini.
……告诉亚瑟我要两张明天晚上普契尼的歌剧票
We're back in business!
我们又回到生意上了
It's money that I love.
我爱钱